S. S. SARUAR JAHAN

🜙 +4915560679186 👼 sjalim71.de@gmail.com 🛅 sssaruarjahan 🕠 sjalim 💌 Ss-Saruar-Jahan 🔹 Tarfost, Trier, DE

SUMMARY

Hello! I am Saruar, and I have worked as a software engineer on mobile applications (iOS) professionally for over 2 years. After that, I moved to Germany to purse my Master's degree. Currently, searching for iOS application developer role as student work job.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Experienced: Swift | Objective-C | Python | Dart Familiar: Java | Javascript | C#

Software Development: GIT | Agile Methodology

PyTorch | TensorFlow | UIKit | SwiftUI | Flutter | iOS Frameworks & Libraries: Database Languages & Tools: SQL | PLSQL, Firebase | MySQL | MSSQL | SQLite

> Others: Microsoft office suite | LATEX Languages: Native: Bengali Fluent: English

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (iOS)

BJIT LIMITED

March 2023 - August 2024

Dhaka

• Feature implementation with Swift, SwiftUI for iOS Mobile application for Japanese Client

• Understanding the requirement of the assigned task & estimating them

• Attending client meetings to communicate about technical queries

• Implement requested features and fix bugs on running project

• Using source control for code management

• R&D on the new technologies to ease up the development

BJIT LIMITED

TRAINEE SOFTWARE ENGINEER(iOS)

November 2022 - February 2023

• Learned Swift, Swift coding patterns, OOP with swift, UIKit, coding de-sign pattern, and Scrum through hands-on

• Develop a News app from scratch to put all my learning together in iOS development.

EDUCATION

University Of Trier, Trier, Germany

Master's of Science in Data Science

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Mirpur Cantonment Public School & College, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School Certificate

Mirpur Bangla School & College, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Secondary School Certificate

October 2024 - Present CGPA: 1.8 (Last Semester)

April 2017 – December 2022

CGPA: 3.285/4

July 2015 - July 2017

GPA: 5.00/5.00

January 2005 - May 2015

GPA: 5.00/5.00

Language

Language	Proficiency Level
English	Professional Proficiency
German	German beginner's level (A2)
Bangla	Native/Fluent
Hindi	Conversational/Intermediate
Urdu	Conversational/Intermediate

ACTIVITIES

- 1^{st} place in BD Apps Top 10 short list with **FARMAR'S APP**.
- Solved more than 300 programming contest problems.
- Participation Intra Aust Programming Contest Fall-2018, Spring 2019.
- Campus Ambassador Program 2021 by BDAPPS.

VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE

BDApps February 2021 – March 2022

Campus Ambassador

- Lead & build a dev team for USSD app development.
- Conduct several events.

AUST ACM LAB - 02

Competitive Programmer

• Participated in several onsite contests.

May 2019 - September 2022

Dhaka

Dhaka

PUBLICATION

Deep Learning based Misogynistic Bangla Text Identification from Social Media | Publication link

• In this paper, we have proposed automatically identifying misogynistic content in Bangla on social media platforms in order to evaluate the problem's challenges.

Detecting Racist Text in Bengali: An Ensemble Deep Learning Framework | Publication link

• In this paper, we have tried to detect those racist comments with NLP and deep learning techniques. We have built a novel dataset in the Bengali Language. Further, we annotated the dataset and conducted data label validation.

A Multiclass Approach to Identify Misogynistic Bangla Text from Social Media | Publication link

- This paper presents a solution to the problem of automatically classifying misogynistic Bengali messages on social media platforms.
- Several procedures have been taken to preprocess the data.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate 1: Flutter & Dart - The Complete Guide (2023 Edition) by Udemy

Certificate 2: Empowering Success Mastering Soft Skills for Thriving in the Modern Workplace by BJIT Academy.

Certificate 3: iOS & Swift - The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp by Udemy

Certificate 4: Campus Ambassador Program Certificate by BDApps

Certificate 5: Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) by University of Michigan.

Certificate 6: Mobile Application Developer (iOS) by ICT DIVISION, Bangladesh Govt.

Signature